Kumar Ram Jarka

LINUX System Engineer

Ulhasnagar – 421001 | MH +91 9604888942 | jarkakumar@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/kumarjarka11370b222

SUMMARY

Skilled Desktop Support Engineer with 4 years of experience providing technical support for various computer, system and office equipment. Successful in installing, upgrading, and configuring innovative applications on Windows & Linux operating systems and providing technical support to optimize workflows and minimize business interruptions. Balances priorities while quickly solving issues to strengthen business processes and performance.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Software Skills (LINUX):</u> Shell scripting, Automating the task, OS installation & Troubleshooting, PXE boot, Users & Group Management. Disk Management, YUM & DNF Package Installation, Grep output of various commands using AWK, SED & GREP tool, SSH, TRACEROUTE, Basic Knowledge of MPLS, ILL, LAN, VLAN, NAT, SIP.

<u>Software Skills (WINDOWS):</u> MS Office, MS Outlook. IBM Lotus Notes, PST Repair, Documenting, OS Installation & Repairs, Encryption & Decryption, User Profile Backup & Repair, Archive Mapping & Access, IT Infrastructure, VPN Configuration, Management Skill, Network Printer & Scanner Installation, OS Hardening, Remote Support, Software Diagnosis, Application Support, Troubleshooting, Ticketing Tools, TCP/IP, Java Configuration, Network Testing, Connectivity Support, DNS, DHCP, Active Directory (AD)

<u>Hardware Skills:</u> Upgrading Peripherals, Laptop Desktop Card Level Repair, All in One System Repair, N Computing & Thin Client Setup, Networking, Network Cable Crimping.

<u>Self-Learned:</u> Building Batch Files Average Level, Deeply Diagnosing the Issue & Fixing from Root Cause, Fixing Software Level Compatibility Issues, VM Ware & Oracle Virtual Box installation and installing server & client OS for practicing, testing & observing behaviour of various input commands.

WORK EXPERIENCE

LINUX System Prosol IT, Marol Andheri Feb 2022 – Till Date Engineer

Project: Byjus Think & Learn PVT. LTD.

Accomplishment

- SHELL Scripting for installation & upgradation of various software at once.
- 2. Automated installation of OS through PXE Boot.
- 3. The ability to manage multiple tasks in a fast-paced trading environment.

Roles & Responsibilities

- 1. Ameyo calling setup & SIP configuration for dealing calls
- 2. Debugging dropped packets, whether at the network, NIC, OS, or application layers.
- 3. Installing software using yum & dnf package management.
- 4. Installing, configuring, and deploying CENTOS 7 & FEDORA 35 Linux systems.
- 5. Managing and monitoring all installed Systems and Infrastructure (Calling Servers).

L2 Remote & Desktop CMS IT Services, Mahape MBP Nov 2021 – Feb 2022 Support Engineer

Project: HDB Financial Services

Accomplishment

- 1. Windows Auto Unattended Installation using Windows Answer File Generator.
- 2. **Pre-installed software windows 10** bootable ISO image using Microsoft Deployment Tool Kit.
- 3. **Batch file scripting** for Enabling, Renaming & Setting up of password for Local Administrator Account & Password Set, Disable Windows Defender Firewall, Creation of Inbound Firewall Rule & Enabling Remote Desktop.

Roles & Responsibilities

- To set up and manage user accounts and permissions to consent access to a network.
- 2. Upholding and testing security, blocking unapproved access.
- 3. Setting up the Organization's computer system to meet specific business goals.
- 4. **Ensure desktop computers interconnection seamlessly** with diverse systems keeping in mind for compatibility factors.
- 5. **Coordinate with vendors** to resolve technical problems with desktop computing equipment and software.

L2 Desktop ITSource Technologies, Andheri Oct 2019 – Oct 2021 Support Engineer

Project: HDFC Ergo General Insurance Company & HDB Financial Services

Accomplishment

- 1. **Batch file scripting** that could install 15+ software at a time saving of **more than 2** hours.
- 2. Laptop ready with domain joined average count of 17 in a day out of 200 in a team completed before the timeline.
- 3. Achieved 100% compliance by regularly updating the systems.

Roles & Responsibilities

- Monitored systems in operation and input commands to troubleshoot areas.
- 2. Remote & on ground support provided to clients to achieve maximum productivity.
- 3. Regularly updating on ticketing maintaining the SLA & follow up for closure of ticket on or before the timeline with client satisfaction.
- 4. **Documenting** the performed troubleshooting steps for future reference & handy for the juniors.
- 5. Following up with vendors to deliver service & parts on time in order to expedite ticket closure.

- 1. Xerox machine & pc complete network setup done in order to ensure high performance.
- 2. 3 clients simultaneously handled at same time issues resolved for all with 100% satisfaction.
- 3. Complete hardware & software issue resolved for pc to ensure maximum productivity for output from embroidery machines.
- 4. **Building Ghost Images** for deploying OS which saves time & speeds up the installation process by **5 times faster**.
- 5. **Specialized in laptop body fabrications** done which saves client money up to Rs.4500/- & fixing technical issues whether software or hardware with accuracy of more than 98%.

G1 Junior Associate
System Engineer

3l Infotech & Vara United, Vashi (Vikarta Enterprises)

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

Project: ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company

Accomplishment

- Upgraded OS overall count of 800 all in one systems including laptops & desktops from windows 7 to windows 10 with activation in a team of 4 members with all user data backup before the deadline which saves time & lot of money for the company.
- 2. After the migration of the system some software were facing **compatibility issues** which were resolved independently & circulated the documentation in the team.
- 3. Provided on ground hardware support to reduce the downtime of the system in the call centre & developer department.

Roles & Responsibilities

- 1. Assessed system hardware and software and suggested modifications to reduce lag time and improve overall speed.
- 2. To enhance the security of the laptop **encryption software** deployed name **SOPHOS Safeguard Encryption** which encrypts the full hard drive.
- Maintained personal repository of technical knowledge used to hone responses and shorten remediation times.
- 4. Achieved 100% in security compliance through OS Hardening (Half Yearly Audit).
- 5. Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.

PROFESSIONAL COURSE

A+ N+	Talentedge, Thane	Α	2015
PC Maintenance	Java Computer Centre, Ulhasnagar	A+	2012
Diploma in Financial Accounts	Java Computer Centre, Ulhasnagar	A++	2011
Red Hat System Administrator	KR Network Cloud, E-Learning	Pursuing	2023

EDUCATION

TYB.Com	Mumbai University IDOL	66%	2019
HSC Commerce	Jai Hind Junior College	66%	2012
SSC	Jhulelal Trust School	68%	2010